A Guide to the Records of the Policy Office: Legislative Guidance Memoranda of Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder, 1990-1994.
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Legislative Guidance Memoranda of the Policy Office of Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder,
1990-1994.
The Library of Virginia
35539
Virginia. Govenor (1990-1994: Wilder).
8.05 cu. ft. (23 boxes)
Administrative Information
Arranged by series.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession 35539 was transferred by Gov. Lawrence Douglas Wilder, October 31, 1996.
Historical Information
Lawrence Douglas Wilder was born in Richmond, Va., on January 17, 1931. He graduated from Virginia Union University in 1951 and afterwards was drafted into the Army, where he served in the Korean War from 1952-1953 and received a bronze star. He then attended the Howard University School of Law and graduated in 1959. Douglas Wilder was elected to the Virginia Senate in 1969 as the first African American member since Reconstruction and served in the Senate for five terms. In 1985, he was elected to the office of Lieutenant Governor as the first African American to be elected to statewide office in Virginia. L. Douglas Wilder won the election for Governor of Virginia in 1989 and served from January 13, 1990 to January 14, 1994. He was the first African American to be elected as Governor in United States.
During the Wilder Administration, the Policy Office was headed by Walter McFarlane, Executive Assistant for Policy, and four Special Assistants: Richard Taylor (Health and Human Resources, and Education), Robert Blue (Finance and Natural Resources), Jeff Nuechterlein (Economic Development and Transportation), and Lynne Porfiri (Administration and Public Safety). The Policy Office was responsible for review and coordination of all policy matters, including: review of proposed legislation from agencies and Cabinet; formulation of the Governor's legislative initiatives; tracking legislation and serving as legislative liaison; review of General Assembly approved legislation submitted to the Governor for signature, amendment or veto; review of death penalty clemency requests, as well as other pardon and restoration of rights requests; review of legal settlements and other legal matters from the Office of the Attorney General's Office; review of proposed regulations; review of all matters pertaining to the judiciary and writs of habeas corpus; review of proposed executive orders; assistance with speech writing; serving as staff for Governor's special commissions; administrative support for Governor's Fellows program; serving as special interest liaison; acting as in-house counsel; and all correspondence with policy implications or pertaining to sensitive or controversial issues requiring legal overview.
Scope and Content
Legislative Guidance Memoranda, 1990-1994, are housed in 23 boxes and are arranged chronologically by year of legislative session, and by Secretarial area thereunder. The legislative guidance memoranda document legislative proposals submitted by Cabinet Secretariats and state agencies, and the subsequent review of the proposals. Initial legislative packages submitted by cabinet secretaries and state agencies include a summary of the legislation, objectives, needs assessment, impacts (internal, external, program/client, budgetary), and may also include correspondence, draft legislation and other background information. Legislative guidance memoranda are decision summaries that consist of summary sheets that may include a brief summary of and justification for the legislative proposals; impacts of the legislation; agency and Attorney General reaction to the legislation; and tracking of required reviews and recommendations of the Dept. of Planning and Budget, Cabinet Secretary, Policy Office, and the Governor's final decision (approve, disapprove or approve with modification). Recommendations include a signature and date. These files may also include supporting documentation such as correspondence, notes, draft legislation, news articles and reports. If approved, the proposals become part of the Governor's legislative package.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Legislative Guidance Memoranda, 1990-1994
Contents List
- Legislative Guidance Memoranda, 1990.
  - Secretary of Administration.
    - General Services, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Information Management, Council on, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Commonwealth, Secretary of, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - General Services, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Personnel and Training, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Economic Development.
    - Agriculture and Consumer Services, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Commerce, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Economic Development, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Employment Commission, Virginia, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Forestry, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Labor and Industry, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Mines, Minerals and Energy, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Racing Commission, Virginia, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Secretary of Education.
    - Education, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Secretary of Finance.
    - State Internal Auditor, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Treasury, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Taxation, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Treasury, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Treasury, Dept. of (Parking Facility Fees), 1990. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Secretary of Health and Human Resources.
    - Social Services, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Social Services, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Deaf and Hard of Hearing, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Health, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Mental Health, Mental Retardation and Substance Abuse Services, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Rehabilitative Services, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Rights for the Disabled, Dept. for, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Aging, Dept. for the, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Health Professionals, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Medical Assistance Services, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Deaf and Hard of Hearing, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Visually Handicapped, Dept. for the, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Health, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Health Professions, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Medical Assistance Services, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Mental Health, Mental Retardation, and Substance Abuse Services, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Aging, Dept. for the, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Social Services, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Secretary of Natural Resources.
    - Air Pollution Control, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Historic Resources, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Marine Resources Commission, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Waste Management, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Air Pollution Control, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Marine Resources Commission, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Waste Management, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Secretary of Public Safety.
    - Alcoholic Beverage Control, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Corrections, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Criminal Justice Services, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - State Police, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Alcoholic Beverage Control, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Aviation, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Corrections, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Criminal Justice, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Military Affairs, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - State Police, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Alcohol Safety Action Program, 1990. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Secretary of Transportation.
    - Motor Vehicles, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Transportation, Dept. of, 1990. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Legislative Proposal Packages.
    - Secretary of Education, 1990. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Secretary of Natural Resources, 1990. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Secretary of Transportation, 1990. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Secretary of Natural Resources, 1990. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Secretary of Public Safety, 1990. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Secretary of Transportation, 1990. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Secretary of Education, 1990. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Secretary of Health and Human Resources, 1990. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Secretary of Economic Development, 1990. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Secretary of Administration, 1990. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Secretary of Education, 1990. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Secretary of Natural Resources, 1990. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Secretary of Transportation, 1990. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Secretary of Education, 1990. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Secretary of Finance, 1990. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Secretary of Health and Human Resources, 1990. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Secretaries - All, 1990. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Secretaries - All, 1990. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Legislative Guidance Memoranda, 1991.
  - Secretary of Administration.
    - General Services, Dept. of, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Human Rights, Council on, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Information Management, Council on, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Secretary of Finance.
    - Taxation, Dept. of, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Taxation, Dept. of, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Treasury, Dept. of the, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Accounts, Dept. of, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Taxation, Dept. of, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Treasury, Dept. of the, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Accounts, Dept. of, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Treasury, Dept. of the, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Natural Resources.
    - Waste Management, Dept. of, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Air Pollution Control, Dept. of, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Marine Resources Commission, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Waste Management, Dept. of, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Conservation and Recreation, Dept. of, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Game and Inland Fisheries, Dept. of, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Historic Resources, Dept. of, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - State Water Control Board, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Air Pollution, Dept of, and State Water Control Board, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Council on the Environment, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - State Water Control Board, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Air Pollution, Dept. of, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Marine Resources Commission, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - State Water Control Board, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Secretary of Public Safety.
    - Alcoholic Beverage Control, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Corrections, Dept. of, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Correctional Education, Dept. of, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Virginia Parole Board, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Youth and Family Services, Dept. of, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Criminal Justice Services, Dept. of, 1991. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - State Police, Dept. of, 1991. (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Legislative Guidance Memoranda, 1992.
  - Secretary of Administration.
    - Virginia Retirement System, 1992. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Retirement System, 1992. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Retirement System, 1992. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - General Services, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - General Services, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - General Services, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Information Management, Council on, 1992. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Information Management, Council on, 1992. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Information Management, Council on, 1992. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Information Management, Council on, 1992. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Information Technology, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Information Technology, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Information Technology, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Information Technology, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Secretary of Economic Development.
    - Agriculture and Consumer Services, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Commerce, Dept. of (v. 1), 1992. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Commerce, Dept. of (v. 2), 1992. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Commerce, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Housing and Community Development, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Labor and Industry, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Minority Business Enterprise, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Employment Commission, 1992. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Secretary of Education.
    - Education, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Education, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Education, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Secretary of Finance.
    - Accounts, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Finance, Secretary of - Support documentation, 1992. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Taxation, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Taxation, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Treasury, Dept. of the, 1992. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Treasury, Dept. of the, 1992. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Health and Human Resources.
    - Aging, Dept. for the, 1992. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Aging, Dept. for the, 1992. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Deaf and Hard of Hearing, Dept. for the, 1992. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Health, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Health, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Health Professions, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Health Professions, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Health Professions, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Health Services and Cost Review Council, 1992. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Medical Assistance Services, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Medical Assistance Services, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Medical Assistance Services, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Mental Health, Mental Retardation and Substance Abuse, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Mental Health, Mental Retardation and Substance Abuse, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Rights for Virginians with Disabilities, Dept. for the, 1992. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Secretary of Public Safety.
    - Alcoholic Beverage Control, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Alcoholic Beverage Control, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Corrections, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Corrections, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Corrections, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Criminal Justice, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Emergency Services, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Emergency Services, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Fire Programs, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Parole Board, Virginia, 1992. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Public Safety, Secretary of - Legislative recommendations (List), 1992. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - State Police, Virginia, 1992. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - State Police, Virginia, 1992. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - State Police, Virginia, 1992. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Youth and Family Services, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Youth and Family Services, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Natural Resources.
    - Air Pollution Control, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Air Pollution Control, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Conservation and Recreation, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Conservation and Recreation, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Historic Resources, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Historic Resources, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Waste Management, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Secretary of Transportation.
    - Motor Vehicles, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Motor Vehicles, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Motor Vehicles, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Motor Vehicles, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Motor Vehicles, Dept. of (Discussion), 1992. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Motor Vehicles, Dept. of (Discussion), 1992. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Motor Vehicles, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Motor Vehicles, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Transportation, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Transportation, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Transportation, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Transportation, Dept. of (Discussion), 1992. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Transportation, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Legislative Proposals, 1992.
  - Legislative Reports (All).
    - Legislative Guidance Memoranda, 1992. (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Legislative Proposals, 1992. (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Legislative Report, 1992. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Economic Development.
    - Agriculture and Consumer Services, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Commerce, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Housing and Community Development, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Labor and Industry, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Minority Business Enterprise, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Employment Commission, 1992. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Secretary of Education.
    - Deaf and Blind, Virginia School for the, 1992. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Education, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Visually Handicapped, Dept. for the, 1992. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Secretary of Finance.
    - Accounts, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Taxation, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Treasury, Dept. of the, 1992. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Secretary of Health and Human Resources.
    - Aging, Dept. for the, 1992. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Deaf and Hard of Hearing, Dept. for the, 1992. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Health, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Health Professions, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Health Services Cost Review Council, 1992. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Medical Assistance Services, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Mental Health, Mental Retardation and Substance Abuse Services, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Rehabilitative Services, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Rights for Virginians with Disabilities, Dept. for, 1992. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Social Services, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Social Services, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Secretary of Natural Resources.
    - Air Pollution Control, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Conservation and Recreation, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Environment, Council on the, 1992. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Historic Resources, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Mines, Minerals and Energy, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Waste Management, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Public Safety.
    - Alcoholic Beverage Control, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Corrections, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Correctional Education, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Criminal Justice, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Emergency Services, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Fire Programs, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Parole Board, Virginia, 1992. (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - State Police, Virginia, 1992. (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Youth and Family Services, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Secretary of Transportation.
    - Motor Vehicles, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Transportation, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Legislative Guidance Memoranda, 1993.
  - Secretary of Administration.
    - Compensation Board, 1993. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Commerce, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - General Services, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Information Management, Council on, 1993. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Personnel and Training, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Retirement System, 1993. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Secretary of Economic Development.
    - Agriculture and Consumer Services, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Commerce, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Commerce, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Commerce, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Economic Development, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Labor and Industry, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Racing Commission, Virginia, 1993. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Secretary of Education.
    - Education, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Secretary of Finance.
    - State Internal Auditor, Dept. of the, 1993. (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Treasury, Dept. of the, 1993. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Secretary of Health and Human Resources.
    - Health, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Health, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Health Professions, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Health Professions, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Medical Assistance Services, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Medical Assistance Services, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Medical Assistance Services, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Mental Health, Mental Retardation and Substance Abuse Services, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Rehabilitative Services, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Rehabilitative Services, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Social Services, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Social Services, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Social Services, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Visually Handicapped, Dept. for the, 1993. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Secretary of Natural Resources.
    - Air Pollution Control, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Conservation and Recreation, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Game and Inland Fisheries, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Marine Resources Commission, 1993. (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Mines, Minerals and Energy, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Waste Management, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Public Safety.
    - Alcoholic Beverage Control, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Alcoholic Beverage Control, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Corrections, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Criminal Justice, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Military Affairs, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Parole Board, Virginia, 1993. (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - State Police, Virginia, 1993. (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Youth and Family Services, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Secretary of Transportation.
    - Aviation, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Transportation, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Pending Memoranda (multiple departments), 1993. (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Legislative Guidance Memoranda, 1994.
  - Secretary of Administration.
    - General Services, Dept. of, 1994. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Secretary of Commerce and Trade.
    - Agriculture and Consumer Services, Dept. of, 1994. (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Commerce and Trade, Secretary of, 1994. (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Economic Development, Dept. of, 1994. (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Housing and Community Development, Dept. of, 1994. (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Housing and Community Development, Dept. of, 1994. (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Labor and Industry, Dept. of, 1994. (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Professional and Occupational Development, Dept. of, 1994. (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Employment Commission, 1994. (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Employment Commission, 1994. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Secretary of the Commonwealth.
    - Commonwealth, Secretary of, 1994. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Secretary of Education.
    - Education, Dept. of, 1994. (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Education, Dept. of, 1994. (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Fine Arts, Virginia Museum of (VMFA), 1994. (Box 20, Folder 6)